hrblock.in 2018-08-26

# Privacy Policy | H&R Block

Block Online Privacy Practices and Principles

H &R Block (India) Private Limited (“H&R Block”) offers a wide range of tax services, including tax preparation, tax planning, and business services in India. Because we offer a variety of services both online (via the Internet) and throughout H&R Block’s nationwide network of offices, H&R Block’s privacy practices may vary depending on how you interact with H&R Block. The following guidelines set forth general privacy principles that apply to information collected on the Website, independent of any particular business relationship you enter into with H&R Block. If you enter into a business relationship with H&R Block as our customer (such as when you are utilizing our tax preparation or other software or online tax preparation tools), we will make you aware of the privacy practices that apply to that particular business or relationship.

These practices do not apply to our physical offices you may visit for services, and these practices do not apply to other affiliates of H&R Block. Those H&R Block affiliates will provide you with their privacy notices when you enter into a business relationship with them. If you are a customer at our physical offices then you will be provided with a privacy policy at our physical office. Our Online Privacy statement does not cover information you provide to the Websites we advertise on and may link to. We encourage you to read the privacy policy on these sites.

Personal Information We Collect and how we use it

When you visit https://www.hrblock.in,you are not required to provide any Personal Information unless you choose to avail our online services or signup for free newsletter or other services which are described below.

Newsletters

When you subscribe to newsletters we collect your email address to e- mail you the newsletters.

Registration

In order to avail our “File It Yourself” / “Online Assisted” tax preparation services you must register yourself on the Website and you must provide your email address, a password. This information is collected for personal identification, to provide the tax preparation services, to allow us to contact you for customer service purpose, to mail you the tax update, newsletter and for marketing communication with you, both online and offline.

Availing a Service

In order to avail the tax preparation services you must provide your name, address, email address, phone number, permanent account number (“PAN”), bank account number, MICR number, income and deductions data, expenses data, asset and income details, vouchers, bank statements, form 16, tax payment challans, debit and credit account numbers and its expiration and any other information as may be required to prepare your tax return. This information is collected for preparation and filing of your Income Tax Return, to complete the payment transaction, customer service purposes, marketing communication with you, both online and offline.

Feedback Form/Client Inquiry Form

When you request services or information from us or provide feedback to us, we collect your personal information like name, email address, phone number, city etc .to provide you the requested information, use it for future correspondence, to improve our services, learn about client filing experience, match you to the nearest office.

Promotion and Sweepstakes

We may sponsor promotions and sweepstakes to give our visitors/clients an opportunity to win great prizes. Information collected by us for such activities may include contact information and survey questions. We use contact information to notify the contest winners and survey information to develop promotions and product improvement.

Expressing an interest in working with H&R Block

Our Website enables you to register your interest in working for us or applying for an advertised vacancy, Information you provide when you apply for employment with H&R Block includes your personal and education details, work experience and this information is used for future communication as may be required.

Web technologies

We may collect information through the following Web technologies: We utilize a software technology called “cookies”. Internet cookies allow us to customize our Website for you by placing small files on your computer as you visit various components of https://www.hrblock.in . Through the use of cookies, we can display only those items that may be of interest to you on a particular site, or make it easier for you to access your account information. In most cases, however, information we collect through Internet cookies does not identify you personally.  
Like most standard Website servers, H&R Block uses log files. Information collected in log files may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We utilize this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. This information is not personally identifiable. When you use certain online tax services, IP addresses are personally identifiable.  
When you use calculators and other tools on our Websites that do not require registration, H&R Block may collect non-identifiable data from such tools, such as the number of people that use a certain tool. H&R Block may also set cookies or clear gifs based upon your use of tools and calculators to help us customize offers and tools to your particular interests. H&R Block will not record or track any data you enter into standalone tools and calculators in any way that identifies you personally, unless we specifically inform you that we are doing so at the time you provide such data.

From time to time we may add or enhance services available on the Website. To the extent these services are provided, and used by you, we will use the information you provide to facilities the service. For example, if you email us with a question, we will use your email address etc. We may also store such information to assist us in making the Website better and easier to use.

How We May Disclose Your Information

Information that H&R Block collects from you is controlled by the Information Technology Act, 2000, other relevant laws, and H&R Block policies. Any information that is collected from you as part of your customer relationship(s) with H&R Block, through a retail office will be governed by the privacy notice that will be provided to you when you become a customer of the specific H&R Block business.

For information collected on https://www.hrblock.in (as described above), H&R Block or any person authorized on its behalf may transfer sensitive personal data or information including any information, to any other body corporate or person in India, or located in any other country, which ensures the same level of data protection that is adhered by H&R Block as provided for under the Rules made under the information technology Act, 2000. H&R Block may also use and disclose such information to the following categories of persons:

Uses and Disclosures by H&R Block. Where permitted by law, H&R Block may use the information collected on this Website to make you aware of products and services offered by H&R Block and its affiliated companies. By using this website, you consent to the transfer of your login credentials to the United States.

Third Parties. We do not share your personal information with non-affiliated third parties for marketing purposes except as permitted by applicable law or with your consent. We do not sell or rent your personal information to third party direct marketers.

Affiliates. H&R Block may provide information it collects to its affiliates as permitted by law. For example, we disclose information to our affiliates in order to respond to your requests for information or services, or to help limit your receipt of marketing materials you have requested not to receive.

Service Providers. Where permitted by applicable law, we may disclose your personal information to service providers who perform business functions or hosting services on our behalf and who may be located outside of India. We require H&R Block service providers to have written contracts that specify appropriate use of your personal information, require them to safeguard your personal information, and prohibit them from making unauthorized or unlawful use of your personal information.

Joint Marketing Arrangements. Where permitted by law, H&R Block may provide information it collects to joint marketers with whom H&R Block has a marketing arrangement We require all joint marketers to have written contracts with us that specify appropriate use of your personal information, require them to safeguard your personal information, and prohibit them from making unauthorized or unlawful use of your personal information.

Persons Who Acquire Our Assets or Business. If H&R Block sells or transfers any of its business or assets, certain information about our clients may be a part of that sale or transfer. In the event of such a sale or transfer, H&R Block will notify you. The notification procedure will be the same as the procedure we use to notify you of a change in our privacy statement as described below.

Persons Who Request Information for Legal Purposes. We may disclose your information to affiliates or non-affiliated third parties when we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is required by law. This may occur in connection with a court order, legal process, or other judicial, administrative or investigative proceeding that produces a request for information from H&R Block.

Government Agency. Information shall be shared with Government agencies mandated under the law to obtain information including sensitive personal data or information for the purpose of verification of identity or for prevention, detection, investigation including cyber incidents, prosecution, and punishment of offences provided the Government agencies states that information so obtained shall not be published or shared with any other person.

We may also disclose aggregate information compiled using your personal information that does not identify you individually or personally. This may include, for example, the total number of visitors to our Website from a particular state, or the average age of a user of our Websites.

Changes to Our Privacy Statement

From time to time, we may change this Online Privacy Policy. The effective date of this policy, as stated below, indicates the last time this policy was revised or materially changed. Checking the effective date below allows you to determine whether there have been changes since the last time you reviewed the Policy.

Effective Date

This policy was last modified in March 2014.

By entering and using its content it will be implied that you have accepted our privacy practices and principles and that you are bound by it. In no case will H&R Block be responsible for any loss/ harm to you on account of you not being updated with any changes in our privacy practices and principles.

Security

H&R Block has implemented generally accepted standards of technology and operational security in order to protect personally identifiable information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. All Personal Information you provide on the Website is transmitted using SSL (Secured Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is coding system which lets your browser automatically encrypts, or scramble, data before you send it to us. All payments on the Website are VeriSign SSL secured. Only authorized H&R Block personnel are provided access to personally identifiable information and these employees have agreed to ensure confidentiality of this information

Social Media Platforms

You may wish to participate in social media platform hosted by H&R Block which we make available to you. The main aim of the social media platform is to facilitate and allow you to share content. However, H&R Block cannot be held responsible if you share personal information on Social media platform that is subsequently used, misused or otherwise appropriate by another user.

Contacting Us With Questions Or UNSUBSCRIBE

If you have questions or concerns or grievances regarding this privacy policy you can email H&R Block’s grievance officer at [info@hrblock.in](mailto:info@hrblock.in).  If at any time you wish to limit the communication you receive from H&R Block, you can click on the “Unsubscribe” link or follow the instruction in each of promotional or marketing e-mail message.
